João Victor Torres Borges

Robotics Engineer, Computer Engineer

Salvador-BA, Brazil

+55 8299801 5259

https://borgesjvt.githubio

https://github.com/BorgesJVT

borgesjvt@gmail.com

Languages

Portuguese

English

Skills

© C++
Libs: Boost, Eigen, OSQP

Python

ROS/ROS2

♦ Gazebo♦ Git♦ • • • •

OpenCV •••••

Machine Learning •

Open Source Contributions ———

ros2 control

ros2_control_demos

I'm a Computer Engineer graduated from the Federal University of Alagoas, Brazil. I have acted as Robotics Engineer, for 2 years, professionaly, and have 5 years of academic experience, working with control, navigation, simulation, SLAM and multirobot coordination. I also have worked with computer vision and embbeded systems, developing prototypes of mobile robots and autonomous systems applications. My strong skills are C++ and ROS for development. Currently, I work at the Brazilian Robotics Institute, in SENAI CIMATEC, on projects related mainly to the Oil and Gas industry.

Working Experience

Fulltime

currently

2019 - Robotics Engineer

SENAI CIMATEC

RBiM is a project of a robot to attend tasks of inspection and intervention in the field of Oil and Gas. Activities developed were the robot dynamic model in an underwater environment, controller design, teleoperation and control of devices. An interface for debugging and data visualization was also implemented.

TRIS project - *Thermal Remote Identification System of Feverish People* raises up, during COVID-19 pandemic, as a virus propagation control tool by assisting in the process of detecting feverish people. The essential modules are face detection and recognition, as well as, temperature estimation. Activities developed were the software architecture design, data acquisition and integration of modules into an optimized pipeline for real time application.

2019 - 2019 Robotics Engineer

Brisa Robotics

Activities developed were software development and integration, mainly stacks like mapping and localization, navigation and WEB dashboard, to launch a differential robot capable of navigate autonomously. Demo work: https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6554061159870316544/

Interships

2017 – 2017 Software Engineer

City Hall IT Department

Activities developed were software development and maintainance for the city hall WEB systems implemented in JAVA. Some of those tasks included database (PostgreSQL) queries, frontend-controller funcionalities and bug fixes.

Education

Study

2011 – 2017

Bachelor in Computer Engineer Federal University of Alagoas - UFAL Thesis: A Case Study for Analysis and Evaluation ORB-SLAM Algo-

rithm

Demo work: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7BjPOosEKhU&t=51s.

Publications

2020 TRIS: Thermal Remote Identification System of Feverish People

International Symposium on Innovation and Technology - SIINTEC PID Controller Synthesis for Network Controlled Second Order

2018 Systems

Brazilian Conference on Automation - CBA